Guide to the Reinhold Riemer Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Reinhold Riemer Papers
1915-1917
RG 121
Yale University Divinity School Library
1.5
(3 boxes)
Notes and papers from Riemer's years at the Yale Divinity School (1915-1917) provide insight into the curriculum and teaching methods at YDS during the first part of the twentieth century. Reinhold Riemer was a Yale Divinity School graduate, Moravian minister, and President of the Moravian College for Women.
Riemer, Reinhold, 1889-1955
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
1889 Sept 28 Born in Russia
1910 B.A., Moravian College
1912 B.D., Moravian Theological Seminary
1912 Aug 11 Ordained in the Moravian Church, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada
1916 B.D., Yale
1917 Yale, Fourth Year Class
1917-22 Minister, Moravian Church in Palmyra, New Jersey
1922- President, Moravian College for Women
1955 Died
Scope and Contents
I. Lecture Notes, 1915-1917, n.d.
II. Term Papers, 1915-1917, n.d.
III. Reviews and Notes, 1915-1917, n.d.
Riemer's notes and writings provide information about the curriculum and teaching methods at the Yale Divinity School during the period that he was a student there, 1915-1917. These notes supplement the papers of various faculty members held by the Yale Divinity Library, including those of Benjamin Wisner Bacon, Harlan Page Beach, Charles Reynolds Brown, Douglas Clyde Macintosh, Frank Chamberlin Porter, Henry Hallam Tweedy, and Williston Walker.
Arrangement
>I. Lecture Notes, 1915-1917, n.d.
II. Term Papers, 1915-1917, n.d.
III. Reviews and Notes, 1915-1917, n.d.
Riemer, Reinhold, 1889-1955; Yale University. Divinity School
- Lecture Notes, 1915-1917, n.d.; Series I
  - Bacon, Benjamin Wisner
    - "Christological Epistles", 1916-1917 (Box 1)
    - "Teaching of Jesus", 1916-1917 (Box 1)
  - Beach, Harlan Page
    - "Missions Administration: The Home Base", 1915-1916 (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Charles Andrew Armstrong
    - "Philosophy of Religion", 1916-1917 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Charles Reynolds
    - "The Minister's Message", 1915-1916 (Box 1)
  - Duncan, George Martin
    - "Epistemology", 1916-1917 (Box 1)
  - Hocking W. E.
    - "N.W. Taylor Lectures" plus Walker and Usher, "Miscellaneous Lectures", 1915-1916 (Box 1)
  - Macintosh, Douglas Clyde
    - "Philosophy of Religion", 1915-1916 (Box 1)
    - "Religious Contemporary Philosophy", 1916-1917 (Box 1)
    - "Systematic Theology", 1916-1917 (Box 1)
  - Porter, Frank Chamberlin
    - "Biblical Theology in the New Testament", 1915-1916 (Box 1)
    - "Old Testament Theology", 1916-1917 (Box 1)
    - "Palestinian Judaism", 1915-1916 (Box 2)
    - "Social Teachings of the New Testament", 1915-1916 (Box 2)
  - Rogers, Arthur Kenyon
    - "The Problem of Error", 1916-1917 (Box 2)
  - Sneath, Elias Hershey
    - "Concept of God in Modern Philosophy", 1915-1916 (Box 2)
    - "History of Modern Ethics", 1916-1917 (Box 2)
  - Tweedy, Henry Hallam
    - "Advanced Homiletics", 1915-1916 (Box 2)
    - "Practical Church Music", 1915-1916 (Box 2)
  - Walker, Williston
    - "History of Christian Doctrine", 1915-1916 (Box 2)
  - Weigle, Luther Allan
    - "Psychology of Childhood", 1916-1917 (Box 2)
    - "The Theory of Religious Education", 1916-1917 (Box 2)
  - Wheaton, H.H.
    - "Service Among Immigrants", 1915-1916 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Lecturers
    - "Hellenistic Judaism", 1916-1917 (Box 2)
    - "Pastoral Problems", 1915-1916 (Box 2)
- Term Papers, 1915-1917, n.d.; Series II
  - "A Theory of Religious Education Based Upon Dewey's Theory of Education", 1917 (Box 3)
  - "Descartes Theory of Knowledge", 1917 (Box 3)
  - "Early Greek Materialism", 1916 (Box 3)
  - "The Epistemology of Royce", n.d. (Box 3)
  - "The Hope of Immortality", 1917 (Box 3)
  - "Horace Bushnell's Christian Nurture", 1916 (Box 3)
  - "How Would I Deal With Miracles in My Preaching?", 1915 (Box 3)
  - "The Methodology of Schleiermacher" (Box 3)
  - "The Preexistence of Christ According to Col. 1:15-17", 1917 (Box 3)
  - "The Problem of Error in Descartes Theory of Knowledge", 1917 (Box 3)
  - "Schleiermacher", 1917 (Box 3)
  - "The Subjective Idealism of Berkeley", 1917 (Box 3)
  - "Survey of the Moravian Missions", 1917 (Box 3)
  - "The Theological Method of Albrecht Ritschl", 1917 (Box 3)
  - "Theories of Atonement", n.d. (Box 3)
- Reviews and Notes, 1915-1917, n.d.; Series III
  - Coffin, H.S.: "University Sermons", 1917 (Box 3)
  - Lichtenberger, F.: "Discourses on Religion", 1916 (Box 3)
  - Paulsen: "Ethics", 1915 (Box 3)
  - Riemer, R. "Veracity", n.d. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous reviews and notes (Box 3)